<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Customer Access Network on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Customer Access Network on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:13:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bi-CAN Aruba/arista Config</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/bi-can_arista_aruba_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/bi-can_arista_aruba_config/</guid>
      <description>BI-CAN Aruba/Arista Config This is an example configuration of how to connect two Aruba spine switches to two Arista switches. This example is from a running system utilizing the bifurcated CAN feature offered in CSM 1.2.
Summary:
 Two Aruba 8325s running in a VSX cluster. Two Arista 7060CX2-32S running MLAG. The Aristas are connected to the Slingshot/HSN network via static MLAG. The Aruba Spine switches are connected to the Aristas with point-to-point OSPF links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAN/cmn With Dual-spine Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/dual_spine_configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/dual_spine_configuration/</guid>
      <description>CAN/CMN with Dual-Spine Configuration The Customer Access Network (CAN) and Customer Management Network (CMN) needs to be connected to both spines in a dual-spine configuration so that each spine can access the outside network. However, the NCNs should only have one default gateway. Therefore, the multi-active gateway protocol (MAGP) on the Mellanox spines can be used to create a virtual router gateway IP address that can direct to either of the spines, depending on the state of the spines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect To The CAN</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/connect_to_the_can/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/connect_to_the_can/</guid>
      <description>Connect to the CAN How to connect to the CAN physically and via layer 3.
There are multiple ways to connect to the Customer Access Network (CAN), both physically and via a layer 3 connection.
Physical Connection to the CAN The physical connection to the CAN is made via the load balancer or the spine switches. The uplink connection from the system to the customer network is achieved by using the highest numbered port(s).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Access Network</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/customer_access_network_can/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/customer_access_network_can/</guid>
      <description>Customer Access Network The Customer Access Network (CAN) provides access from outside the customer network to services, non-compute nodes (NCNs), and User Access Nodes (UANs) in the system. This allows for the following:
 Clients outside of the system:  Log in to each of the NCNs and UANs. Access web UIs within the system (e.g. Prometheus, Grafana, and more). Access the Rest APIs within the system. Access a DNS server within the system for resolution of names for the webUI and REST API services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Externally Exposed Services</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/externally_exposed_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/externally_exposed_services/</guid>
      <description>Externally Exposed Services The following services are exposed on the Customer Access Network (CAN). Each of these services requires an IP address on the CAN subnet so they are reachable on the CAN. This IP address is allocated by the MetalLB component.
Services under Istio Ingress Gateway and Keycloak Gatekeeper Ingress share an ingress, so they all use the IP allocated to the Ingress.
Each service is given a DNS name that is served by the External DNS service to make them resolvable from the site network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metallb Peering With Arista Edge Router</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/bi-can_arista_metallb_peering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/bi-can_arista_metallb_peering/</guid>
      <description>MetalLB Peering with Arista Edge Router This is an example configuration of how to connect a pair of Arista switches to MetalLB running inside of Kubernetes.
Prerequisites  Pair of Arista switches already connected to the high-speed network. Updated System Layout Service (SLS) file that has the CHN network configured.  Example Configuration Below is a snippet from an upgraded SLS.
&amp;#34;CHN&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;Name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;CHN&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;FullName&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Customer High-Speed Network&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;IPRanges&amp;#34;: [ &amp;#34;10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Required Labels If CAN Is Not Configured</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/required_labels_if_can_is_not_configured/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/required_labels_if_can_is_not_configured/</guid>
      <description>Required Labels if CAN is Not Configured Some services on the system are required to access services outside of the HPE Cray EX system. If the Customer Access Network (CAN) is not configured on the system, these services will need to be pinned to ncn-m001 because that is the only node that has external access. See Customer Access Network (CAN) for more implications if CAN is not configured.
The label used for scheduling these services is no_external_access:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot CAN Issues</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/troubleshoot_can_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/customer_access_network/troubleshoot_can_issues/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot CAN Issues Various connection points to check when using the CAN and how to fix any issues that arise.
The most frequent issue with the Customer Access Network (CAN) is trouble accessing IP addresses outside of the HPE Cray EX system from a node or pod inside the system.
The best way to resolve this issue is to try to ping an outside IP address from one of the NCNs other than ncn-m001, which has a direct connection that it can use instead of the Customer Access Network (CAN).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
