<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1.2 on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1.2 on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:13:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/scripts/sls/sls_utils/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/scripts/sls/sls_utils/readme/</guid>
      <description>This is a reusable Python library for safely interacting with SLS network data (in JSON format).
The library has been tested against Python version 3.6 and up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade Automation</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/scripts/upgrade/upgrade_automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/scripts/upgrade/upgrade_automation/</guid>
      <description>Upgrade Automation This document describes how we automate upgrade process. In a nutshell, an upgrade is:
 Upload new artifacts into a running system Rebuild each NCN with the newly uploaded images Deploy new charts after all NCNs are upgraded.  Prerequisites Everything we need before upgrading an NCN.
 NOTE:
The prerequisites.sh script is required to run on both ncn-m001 and ncn-m002. If an action is only needed to run once, developers must add logic to avoid running this action both times the script is executed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SLS Updates Expert Mode</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/scripts/sls/expert_mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/scripts/sls/expert_mode/</guid>
      <description>SLS Updates Expert Mode The 1.2 SLS Upgrader aims to make the upgrade of SLS from pre-CMS 1.2 to CSM 1.2 as seamless as possible. However, certain system constraints and subnet sizes quickly necessitate overriding standard input.
Key Takeaways
 EXPERT MODE: requires both an iterative (offline) process and command line override values. The output from the upgrade is a file, not uploaded live to the system. The output logs from an upgrade run should be reviewed to ensure that input values and upgrader subnetting has the desired effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade SLS Offline From 1.0.x To Csm 1.2</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/scripts/sls/readme.sls_upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/scripts/sls/readme.sls_upgrade/</guid>
      <description>Upgrade SLS Offline from CSM 1.0.x to CSM 1.2 Abstract During the update of SLS,at a minimum, answers to the following questions must be known prior to upgrading:
 By default in 1.2 non-administrative user traffic will be migrated from the CAN to the CHN while minimizing changes. If you want it to continue to come in via the CAN, or if the site is Air-gapped, specify the correct options Will user traffic (non-administrative) come in via the CAN, CHN or is the site Air-gapped?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stage 0 - Prerequisites And Preflight Checks</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/stage_0_prerequisites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/stage_0_prerequisites/</guid>
      <description>Stage 0 - Prerequisites and Preflight Checks  Note: CSM-1.0.1 or higher is required in order to upgrade to CSM-1.2.0
 Abstract Stage 0 has several critical procedures which prepares and verify if the environment is ready for upgrade. First, the latest docs RPM is installed; it includes critical install scripts used in the upgrade procedure. Next, the current configuration of the System Layout Service (SLS) is updated to have necessary information for CSM 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stage 1 - Ceph Image Upgrade</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/stage_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/stage_1/</guid>
      <description>Stage 1 - Ceph image upgrade   Run ncn-upgrade-ceph-nodes.sh for ncn-s001. Follow output of the script carefully. The script will pause for manual interaction.
ncn-m001# /usr/share/doc/csm/upgrade/1.2/scripts/upgrade/ncn-upgrade-ceph-nodes.sh ncn-s001  NOTE: You may need to reset the root password for each node after it is rebooted
 Known Issues:
  It is possible to encounter an error like shown below. If this is the case, then re-run the same command for the node upgrade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stage 2 - Kubernetes Upgrade From 1.19.9 To 1.20.13</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/stage_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/stage_2/</guid>
      <description>Stage 2 - Kubernetes Upgrade from 1.19.9 to 1.20.13 Stage 2.1   Run ncn-upgrade-master-nodes.sh for ncn-m002. Follow output of the script carefully. The script will pause for manual interaction.
ncn-m001# /usr/share/doc/csm/upgrade/1.2/scripts/upgrade/ncn-upgrade-master-nodes.sh ncn-m002   Repeat the previous step for each other master node excluding ncn-m001, one at a time.
  Stage 2.2   Run ncn-upgrade-worker-nodes.sh for ncn-w001. Follow output of the script carefully. The script will pause for manual interaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stage 3 - Service Upgrades</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/stage_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/stage_3/</guid>
      <description>Stage 3 - CSM Service Upgrades   Prepare assets:
ncn-m002# CSM_RELEASE=csm-1.2.0   Internet Connected
  Set the ENDPOINT variable to the URL of the directory containing the CSM release tarball.
In other words, the full URL to the CSM release tarball will be ${ENDPOINT}${CSM_RELEASE}.tar.gz
NOTE This step is optional for Cray/HPE internal installs.
ncn-m002# ENDPOINT=https://put.the/url/here/   Run the script
ncn-m002# /usr/share/doc/csm/upgrade/1.2/scripts/upgrade/prepare-assets.sh --csm-version [CSM_RELEASE] --endpoint [ENDPOINT]     Air Gapped (replace the PATH_TO below with the location of the CSM release tarball)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stage 4 - Ceph Upgrade</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/stage_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/stage_4/</guid>
      <description>Stage 4 - Ceph Upgrade Addresses CVEs  CVE-2021-3531: Swift API denial of service. CVE-2021-3524: HTTP header injects via CORS in RGW. CVE-2021-3509: Dashboard XSS via token cookie. CVE-2021-20288: Unauthorized global_id reuse in cephx.  IMPORTANT:
  This upgrade is performed using the ceph orchestrator. The upgrade includes all fixes from v15.2.9 through to v15.2.15 listed here Ceph version index   Procedure Upgrade   Check to ensure the upgrade is possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stage 5 - Perform NCN Personalization</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/stage_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/stage_5/</guid>
      <description>Stage 5 - Perform NCN Personalization Procedure   Set the root user password and SSH keys before running NCN personalization. The location where the password is stored in Vault has changed since previous CSM versions. See Configure the Root Password and Root SSH Keys in Vault.
  If custom configuration content was merged with content from a previous CSM installation, merge the new CSM configuration in with it in the csm-config-management git repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.0.0 Or Later To 1.2.0 Upgrade Process (wip)</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 03:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/upgrade/1.2/readme/</guid>
      <description>CSM 1.0.0 or later to 1.2.0 Upgrade Process (WIP) #NOTE: this is a WIP doc
Introduction This document is intended to guide an administrator through the upgrade process going from Cray Systems Management v1.0 to v1.2. When upgrading a system, this top-level README.md file should be followed top to bottom, and the content on this top level page is meant to be terse. See the additional files in the various directories under the resource_material directory for additional reference material in support of the processes/scripts mentioned explicitly on this page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
