<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security And Authentication on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-09/operations/security_and_authentication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security And Authentication on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 05:30:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-09/operations/security_and_authentication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Add LDAP User Federation</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-09/operations/security_and_authentication/add_ldap_user_federation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 05:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-09/operations/security_and_authentication/add_ldap_user_federation/</guid>
      <description>Add LDAP User Federation Add LDAP user federation using the Keycloak localization tool.
Prerequisites LDAP user federation is not currently configured in Keycloak. For example, if it was not configured in Keycloak when the system was initially installed or the LDAP user federation was removed.
Procedure   Prepare to customize the customizations.yaml file.
If the customizations.yaml file is managed in an external Git repository (as recommended), then clone a local working tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Cray Ex Cabinet Global Default Password</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-09/operations/security_and_authentication/change_ex_cabinet_global_default_password/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 05:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-09/operations/security_and_authentication/change_ex_cabinet_global_default_password/</guid>
      <description>Change Cray EX Cabinet Global Default Password This procedure changes the global default credential on HPE Cray EX liquid-cooled cabinet embedded controllers (BMCs). The chassis management module (CMM) controller (cC), node controller (nC), and Slingshot switch controller (sC) are generically referred to as &amp;ldquo;BMCs&amp;rdquo; in these procedures.
Prerequisites  HPE Cray EX 1.4.2 software is installed and operating. The Cray command line interface (CLI) tool is initialized and configured on the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisioning A Liquid-cooled Ex Cabinet Cec With Default Credentials</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-09/operations/security_and_authentication/provisioning_a_liquid-cooled_ex_cabinet_cec_with_default_credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 05:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-09/operations/security_and_authentication/provisioning_a_liquid-cooled_ex_cabinet_cec_with_default_credentials/</guid>
      <description>Provisioning a Liquid-Cooled EX Cabinet CEC with Default Credentials This procedure provisions a Glibc compatible SHA-512 administrative password hash to a cabinet environmental controller (CEC). This password becomes the Redfish default global credential to access the CMM controllers and node controllers (BMCs).
This procedure does not provision Slingshot switch BMCs. Slingshot switch BMC default credentials must be changed using the procedures in the Slingshot product documentation. Refer to &amp;ldquo;Change Switch BMC Passwords&amp;rdquo; in the Slingshot product documentation for more information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating The Liquid-cooled Ex Cabinet Cec With Default Credentials After A Cec Password Change</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-09/operations/security_and_authentication/updating_the_liquid-cooled_ex_cabinet_default_credentials_after_a_cec_password_change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 05:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-09/operations/security_and_authentication/updating_the_liquid-cooled_ex_cabinet_default_credentials_after_a_cec_password_change/</guid>
      <description>Updating the Liquid-Cooled EX Cabinet CEC with Default Credentials after a CEC Password Change This procedure changes the credential for liquid-cooled EX cabinet chassis controllers and node controller (BMCs) used by CSM services after the CECs have been set to a new global default credential.
NOTE: This procedure does not provision Slingshot switch BMCs (RouterBMCs). Slingshot switch BMC default credentials must be changed using the procedures in the Slingshot product documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
